翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
To answer this question, we need only extrapolate from what we just did.
要回答这个问题，只需从刚才的情况来推断
We know, for example, that going from capacity 100 to 101 required us to create and fill 101 memory boxes.
我们知道从容量为100增加到101需要创建并填满101个内存盒子
That was this picture here.
就是这张图片
To go from 101 to 102 is 102 memory boxes, and so forth.
从101到102需要102个内存盒子，以此类推
And so ultimately, everything boils down to what is the sum of 101 plus 102 plus dot, dot, dot plus 1,000.
所以一切可以归结为 101+102+...+1000
So this is a math problem you might not right now feel comfortable knowing how to solve.
这是一个你现在可能觉得不知道如何解决的数学问题
And so one approach is to go to Wolfram Alpha, which is a handy tool.
一种方法是使用方便的 Wolfram Alpha
And we can just say equals this.
等于这个
And we'll add them all up.
会把它们加起来
And we'll say, around 500,000, which gives us our answer.
答案是大约50万
Now we don't want to be totally dependent on Wolfram Alpha.
现在我们不想完全依赖于 Wolfram Alpha
So in this class later, we're going to use a number of different tricks.
所以在这节课后续部分，我们将使用一些不同的技巧
And so here, the trick that is best, the way that you could actually do it without consulting some external tool
这里不使用某些外部工具的情况下，你做到这点最好的诀窍是
would be to keep in mind that the sum of 1 plus 2 plus 3 plus dot dot dot up to n is equal to n times n plus 1 over 2.
记住1+2+3+...N 的和等于 N*(N+1)/2
This is something you surely learned at some point.
你某个时候学过
You might have forgotten it.
可能忘了
There's a whole link here if you want to read about why that's true.
这个链接解释这为什么是真的
And so we can say that the sum of the numbers 101 to 1,000
所以我们可以说，数字101到1000的总和
is going to be not that much bigger than this sum.
不会比这个总和大很多
Because those first 100 numbers aren't very large.
因为前100个数字不是很大
So this last little bit, we can approximate it
最后一点点可以近似计算
by just doing 1,000 times 1,000 plus 1 divided by 2,
只要做1000 *(1000+1)/2
which is around 500,000.
也就是大约50万
So that's one way to do it.
这是一种方法
So let's compare side by side.
让我们并排比较一下
This is what our S list was capable of.
这是 SLList
Whenever you insert into an S list,
每当插入到 SLList 时
what we show on the y-axis.
y 轴上显示的内容
is the total time to complete all of those inserts.
是完成所有插入的总时间
Some in other words, inserting 20,000 items in this theoretical plot took only 0.00002 seconds.
换句话说，在这个理论图中插入2万项只用了0.00002秒
Inserting 40,000 was 0.00004.
插入4万是0.00004
And this is a purely theoretical number.
这是一个纯粹的理论数字
This is not an actual experiment.
这不是真正的实验
However, if we ran an experiment,
然而，如果我们做个实验
we would really expect to get a straight line.
真的希望得到一条直线
So this straight line indicates that the operations for the S list are all constant time because the integral of a constant is a line.
这条直线表明，SLList 的运算都是常数时间，因为常数的积分是一条直线
By contrast, if we look at the A list, which is much slower--
相比之下，看一下 AList，它的速度要慢得多
and the focus of our attention right now and thus we get a bigger font--
我们关注的焦点就是字体变得更大了...
what we see is that it's actually a parabola.
它实际上是一条抛物线
So that inserting 20,000 items is not nearly as slow as 100,000 items.
插入2万项远不如插入10万项慢
And in fact, inserting 100,000 items,
事实上，插入10万项
if we do the exact same Wolfram Alpha type trick,
如果我们同样使用 Wolfram Alpha
we'll see it's around 5 billion new containers, new memory boxes.
会看到大约50亿个新的容器，新的存储盒
That's a lot.
太多了
And since computers operate at the speed of around gigahertz,
由于计算机的运行速度约为千兆赫兹
that is they do about a billion things per second,
也就是每秒大约做10亿件事
it's no big surprise that inserting 100,000 items took seconds.
插入10万项需要几秒钟也就不足为奇了
So if you think 5 billion divided by 1 billion,
50亿除以10亿
it's around 5 seconds.
大约5秒
My computer did a little better.
我的电脑稍微好一点
So it's a little faster than a gigahertz.
它比千兆赫兹快一点
Just a rough rule of thumb.
这只是个粗略的经验
And so this parabola actually tells us
这条抛物线实际上告诉我们
that as our list gets bigger, it takes longer and longer for the operations to complete.
随着链表越来越大，完成操作所需的时间也越来越长
In other words, the time per operation is linear.
换句话说，每次操作的时间是线性的
And the integral of a line is, of course, a parabola.
直线的积分当然是抛物线
And this right here is unacceptable.
这是不可接受的
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）